

HARRY SOLSEM

Teglverksfaret 16, 1405 Langhus +47 91 60 46 00 DOB: 13 June 1970 harry@solsem.no LinkedIn

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

With more than 30 years of experience, I prioritize, in my role as a leader, creating a safe learning environment for my colleagues, where it is allowed to make mistakes, and I ensure that lessons are learned from the mistakes that are made. I am analytical, value order, pragmatic, solution-oriented, and motivated to facilitate success for my colleagues and myself in achieving results together as a team.

I have extensive technical competence from all phases of digital product development using Microsoft technologies, in addition to extended experience working with and coaching teams into using agile methodologies, plus experience in management of technical it-resources in international working environments.

By hiring me, you will gain an employee with extensive experience who consistently delivers quality work and is always seeking areas for improvement. I thrive in leadership roles where I take responsibility for delivering results and facilitating learning among my colleagues.

EXPERIENCE

Head of department, Riverty, Oslo 2023.09 - today

Riverty is a Fintech company that offers new perspectives on financial solutions. Overall responsibility for recruiting, retaining, and ensuring that my engineers undergo personal development in accordance with the company's overall strategy and the department's wishes and needs. I have also led leaders in my organization. Along with department heads in our other development departments across Europe, I have been responsible for resources working in interdisciplinary product teams. I have, together with my colleagues from our other development departments across Europe, been part of a senior leadership group, responsible for synchronizing related processes. My department consists of 50 sofware, qa, security engineers and architects.

Consultant, The Norwegian Thyroid Organization (STOFO), Oslo 2023.05 – 2023.05

Stofo is a voluntary patient organization for people with thyroid conditions.

Aiding and consultant to the general secretary with strategy clarifications, organizational development, recruitment, and miscellaneous office tasks in running the administration of the organization.

Engineering Manager, Neonomics AS, Oslo 2021.08 - 2023.03

Neonomics is a software house delivering payment products based on psd2-directive. Department manager with 11 software engineers, distributed into two interdisciplinary product teams utilizing agile methodology. I had tasks in resource-scaling, recruitment, create and maintain an environment where engineers thrive and develop them according to the strategy of the company. I had the technical responsibility for all services and products belonging to the payment domain. I was a part of the leadership-team in the techsection of the company.

Senior Manager, KPMG AS, Oslo 2021.01 - 2021.08

KPMG is a global network of professional firms providing Audit, Tax and Advisory services. Consulting on project- and change management. Writing offers, development of framework for agile project execution, with special focus on the Scrum methodology. I was assisting the other departments sharing my framework and advising on the use of agile methodologies.

Page 1 Version 16.4.24

CV - Harry Solsem

Project manager, Tech Lead, <u>DNB</u>, Bergen og Oslo 2017.10 - 2021.01

DNB is Norway's largest financial services group and one of the largest in the Nordic region in terms of market capitalisation. Project manager on multiple simultaneous projects in the IT-Security, Risk management and Quality department. Running projects based on the Prince2 methodology. Scrum master for two projects, administration, and interface to external suppliers of software development services. Leading and consulting of developers working in the Microsoft stack. Advisor as agile coach on initial use of Scrum as methodology.

Architect, Web Services Technology AS, Bergen 2015.5 - 2017.10

WST was a software house building a portal solution for an insurance specialist system. Accountable for design, implementation and maintenance of CI values chain built using TeamCity and OctoDeploy. Consulting on porting of application from Java into C#, Javascript, XSL/XML. Supporting the transition and training of my colleagues on transition from Java to Microsoft technologies and tools.

Project manager, Scrum Master, Sharecat Solutions AS Bergen, 2013.2 - 2015.05

Sharecat is a software house creating software solutions for sharing technical reusable data in projects for the supplier industry in the oil

Project management of delivery project for adaption and implementation of our catalogue service to customer. This project had a scope of 8 MNOK, with an organisation up to 15 people. The project was executed by using a mix of Prince2 and agile methodology. In another role I was responsible for implementing, usage and training of agile methodology in the whole organisation. I held the role of Scrum master for 3 multilocation and multicultural teams.

Service Delivery Manager, Project manager, Ventelo AS, Kristiansand 2010.3 - 2012.6

Ventelo was a mobile operator in the business and consumer marked.

I held the role as interface between IT and the other departments in the organization. I was responsible for distributing tasks to my colleagues and following up on them during execution. Project manager for a software development project that was using Prince2 methodology.

Multiple employers, 1995 – 2010

I have held several technical operative positions that has given me extended experience in all phases of digital product development, operations of IT-systems and working in project teams. More details on my Linkedinprofil.

EDUCATION

Project management, BI Norwegian Business School, 2018.08 - 2019.12

Module based 30 credit study in project management.

Various courses, Agder College, 1999.08 - 2000.05

Bachelor level classes in various topics in software design, 33 credits.

Høyskolekandidat, Norges Høyskole for Informasjonsteknologi, 1992.08 - 1994.05

Software design and related subjects, 120 credits

SERTIFICATIONS

Prosci Change Manager Practitioner, 2024
Scrum Product Owner, SCPO AgileLean House AS, 2021
Prince2Agile Foundation, Holte Academy, 2019
Lean Six Sigma, Yellow Belt, DNB, 2018
Prince2 Practitioner, Holte Consulting AS, 2016
Prince2 Foundation, Holte Consulting AS, 2014
ITIL Foundation, Glasspaper, 2012

Page 2 Version 16.4.2024

ELECTED POSITIONS

Member of the board, Norwegian Thyroid Organization, 2020-td Member of the board, Langhus 1405 Co-ownership Apartments, 2021-td Member of national tariff committee, <u>NITO</u>, 2014-2023

LANGUAGES

Norwegian, native language English, C2 level

METHODOLOGIES

- Scrum
- Kanban
- Lean
- ProsciChangeManagement
- Prince2
- Prince2 Agile
- ITIL v2

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Turbo PascalAssembler
- Ada
- Delphi
- Basic
- Visual Basic
- Borland C++
- C
- Java
- Javascript
- C#
- SQL
- HTML

TOOLS

- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Microsoft Visual Studio Code
- Sql Management Studio

FRAMEWORKS

- Microsoft Foundation Classes
- Microsoft.NET

Page 3 Version 16.4.2024